ihs.com 2004-12-04

# IHS Privacy Statement

Products

>>Standards

>>Military Specifications

>>Regulations

>>Parts Information

>>Validated Design

>>Document Management

>>Enterprise Portals

>>IHS Applications

| 

####  Privacy Statement for IHS

Your right to privacy and to protect your personal information is important to IHS. We recognize that when you provide us with information about yourself, you trust us to act in a responsible manner. 

The following discloses our information gathering and usage practices for www.ihs.com, www.ihsengineering.com, www.ihsgroup.com, global.ihs.com, and www.techsavvy.com. This site contains links to other Web sites, but IHS is not responsible for the privacy practices of other Web sites or companies.

**General Principals.**   Information Handling Services Group, Inc., and its affiliates, IHS Energy and IHS Engineering ("IHS" or "we") respect our customers’ wishes with regard to the collection, use and transfer of certain personal information. Personal information as we use it here refers to certain data about an identified or identifiable individual, such as set forth in the European Community Directive on Data Protection (the "EU Directive"). Proper use of personal information is of a high priority to our company, particularly as we are in the data gathering business. We self-certify our policies to the U.S. Department of Commerce Safe Harbor Program (see <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>). IHS is committed to protecting its users’ personal information in accordance with the privacy principles set forth in the Safe Harbor Program, as well as other applicable laws and regulations. This Privacy Policy is additionally incorporated into and is a part of the Terms and Conditions of Use of IHS’ online use and/or online access of products and services. 

**Types of Data Collection.**   IHS operates globally, with offices and operations in over 60 countries. While our primary data centers are in the United States, we will transfer certain information provided by customers to the appropriate office, agent or consultant in order to deliver the products and services requested by our clients. In addition to collecting information via telephone calls, electronic mail and voicemail, IHS may collect, process, use and transfer personally identifiable information directly from its users when the user voluntarily enters information during the registration process. Additionally, use of the various IHS websites may also result in data being collected, processed and transferred. This information may be received by IHS as part of the standard electronic greeting between your computer, the network, and our servers and typically consists of network routing information, equipment (browser) information, date and time. At this time our server will also query your computer to see if there are "cookies" previously set by IHS to facilitate the log in process. Some IHS websites use cookies to collect information about visitors’ use of its website and to enhance the type of website procedures used by IHS. Cookies collected may include the following information: a unique identifier, user preferences and profile information used to personalize the content shown to the individual users. You may be able to set your web browser to alert you when a cookie is being used, and may use your browser to accept or reject the cookie; additionally, you may also disable the cookie feature on your browser entirely.

**Types of Data Collected and How We Use It.**   In the paragraph above, we described how we collect certain information, including personal information. The types of personally identifiable information which IHS may collect are primarily used for business contact information. This information may include your e-mail address, internet domain, IP address, full name, title, company affiliation, address, and work phone numbers. IHS currently uses the information for the purposes of providing its users with information or products requested by the user, for providing information on extent of use, whether or not requested by user, to provide customized product and service information, and to allow the user to voluntarily participate in mailings or other events. Additionally, if users of our website are already our customers, or become our customers during the online registration process, we will use personally identifiable user information to provide the user with product service, updates, information and alerts. IHS may also disclose personal information, without notice, if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (i) comply with legal process served on IHS; or (ii) protect and defend IHS's property rights in and to its products, or the security or safety of its users and website.

**Notice to Employees.**   IHS may collect personal information from its employees. This information may be transferred between IHS and its affiliates. Personal information on employees of IHS and its affiliates will only be used in accordance with the IHS Human Resources policy and other appropriate and reasonable guidelines.

**Choices and Preferences.**   IHS allows its customers to opt-out of email marketing that may result from use of the site. The ability to do so is offered through the registration process and by links in the email marketing materials. Customers may also sent an opt out message to [customerservice@ihsenergy.com](mailto:customerservice@ihsenergy.com) or [change_email@ihs.com](mailto:change_email@ihs.com). Customers may also update or change their registration profile, including changing the email marketing preferences. There are a few limited exceptions to this opt out ability, but notice is always provided in such communications. The exceptions include: providing updates and patches to currently licensed products, security related information, customer service information for currently licensed products, product downloads, training class information, contract or license related information for currently licensed products.

IHS customers may also change or update their profile (entered by the user during the registration process, or in some cases, by IHS from information provided by its corporate customers if the individual user is an employee of a corporate customer who participates in IHS Energy’s "Single Sign On Process"). To change your profile information, please login as usually and follow the prompts to "update my profile." If you need help with this process, please contact [ customerservice@ihsenergy.com](mailto:customerservice@ihsenergy.com) or [change_email@ihs.com](mailto:change_email@ihs.com).

**Security:**   IHS takes very seriously the need to protect all personal information from unauthorized access or disclosure. IHS does not lend, lease or sell any personal information collected from its users. Other steps to protect personal information include password protected log-in, ability to audit system access, and robust security computer systems, such as firewalls and screens in place on all of our servers and computer systems. We believe that our security measures provide reasonable barriers against disclosure, unauthorized access, alteration or destruction of personal information in accordance with generally accepted industry standards. Additionally, any IHS employees who have access to personal information are bound by IHS confidentiality obligations.

**Enforcement.**   IHS has established internal procedures to monitor our compliance with the Safe Harbor Program and applicable privacy laws. Part of our compliance is performing an annual review of our privacy policy, including internal audits and reviews by third party computer and security consultants, as appropriate.

Any user who feels that his or her personal information has been misused should direct any questions or complaints to [customerservice@ihsenergy.com](mailto:customerservice@ihsenergy.com) or [change_email@ihs.com](mailto:change_email@ihs.com). IHS will then take reasonable steps to investigate such questions or complaints. If a user feels that IHS has not appropriately handled the complaint or question, they may then send a written description of their complaint to Legal Department, IHS Energy or IHS Engineering, who will contact the user to try and resolve his or her concerns. IHS will cooperate with the European Union Data Protection Authorities in the applicable European Union Member States and data protection authorities under any applicable privacy laws to resolve the issues.

Some IHS Web pages use VeriSign for processing secure credit card orders. VeriSign Privacy Statement: [http://www.verisign.com/truste/index.html ](http://www.verisign.com/truste/index.html)

IHS uses ClickAction to deliver e-mail messages to IHS customers and Web site users. Every message comes with unsubscribe information. ClickAction Privacy Statement: <http://www.clickaction.com/site/privac.html>

#### Notification of Change

If IHS decides to change its privacy policy, those changes will be posted here and on other IHS Web sites. Please refer to this page if you have questions about IHS activities. If you have questions about the IHS privacy policy, you can contact:   

Doug Marshall  
Director of Marketing  
IHS Group   
15 Inverness Way East   
Englewood, CO 80112
